<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-15T08:46:33.378Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-15T08:46:33.378Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.7.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auto-Generated Social Media Images]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340136</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/auto-generated-social-media-images/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:34:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been thinking about social media images again. You know, the images that (can) show up when you share a link in places like Twitter, Facebook, or iMessage. You’re essentially leaving money on the table without them, because they …
The post Auto-Generated Social Media Images appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is SendGrid? SMTP Email Newsletter Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>609d63e962ab9107fe5aa2ce</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-sendgrid-smpt-email-newsletter-tutorial/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:31:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You may have heard of the term SMTP before, and wondered what it is. SMTP is a common method for handling email messages. Today I am going to explain what SMTP is, and how to use an SMTP provider such as SendGrid to send emails from your address. What Is]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[React for Beginners: Complete React Cheatsheet for 2021]]></title>
        <id>609ea83362ab9107fe5aa920</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/react-for-beginners-cheatsheet/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:17:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the React for Beginners guide. It's designed to teach you all the core React concepts that you need to know to start building React applications in 2021. I created this resource to give you the most complete and beginner-friendly path to learn React from the ground up. By]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Development for Beginners – Learn Basic HTML and CSS to Build Your First Web Page]]></title>
        <id>609e8c2162ab9107fe5aa77d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/web-development-for-beginners-basic-html-and-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T17:13:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever wondered how websites are built and designed? Do you want to learn the art of web development but you're not that tech savvy – yet? Well, then this tutorial is for you. It's an introduction to Web Development for beginners so you can learn the basics even if]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Stylesheet Feature Flags With Sass !default]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340343</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/creating-stylesheet-feature-flags-with-sass-default/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:14:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[!default is a Sass flag that indicates conditional assignment to a variable — it assigns a value only if the variable was previously undefined or null. Consider this code snippet:
$variable: 'test' !default;
To the Sass compiler, this line …
The post Creating Stylesheet Feature Flags With Sass !default appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nathan Babcock</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML Boilerplates]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340403</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/html-boilerplates/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:13:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manuel Matuzović goes line-by-line through a boilerplate HTML document. I like it. It’s a good reference and has a lot of the same type of stuff I tend to put in the main HTML template. It makes me think about …
The post HTML Boilerplates appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevTools for CSS layouts 2021 edition]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340490</id>
        <link href="https://chenhuijing.com/blog/devtools-for-css-layouts-2021-edition/#%F0%9F%9A%B2"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T23:22:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chen Hui Jing covers some recent movement in DevTools:
Firefox’s grid inspector was pretty full-featured from the get-to and released together with CSS grid in Firefox 52. It was constantly improved upon since. Chrome added a basic grid inspector 
…
The post DevTools for CSS layouts 2021 edition appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2021 Design Systems (Survey/Courses)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340573</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/2021-design-systems-survey-courses/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T22:55:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My friends at Sparkbox are doing a survey on design systems, as they do each year. Go ahead and fill it out if you please. Here are the results from last year. In both 2019 and 2020, the vibe was …
The post 2021 Design Systems (Survey/Courses) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create an Email Newsletter [2021 Tutorial] – Design, Layout, Send]]></title>
        <id>609414f32cd0545b5e943526</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-create-an-email-newsletter-design-layout-send/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T21:19:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you manage a large community, chances are you need a way to communicate updates to your members quickly and efficiently. An email newsletter can be a very effective way to do so. In this article, I am going to provide some tips and suggestions for maximizing the impact and]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Software Testing? The 10 Most Common Types of Tests Developers Use in Projects]]></title>
        <id>609952396008950828b3ea8d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/types-of-software-testing/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T19:27:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Software development and testing go hand in hand. And in the era of agile software development, with quick releases of small iterations, you should do testing more and more frequently.  In order to perform effective testing, you need to know about the different types of testing and when you should]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[React Tutorial – How to Work with Multiple Checkboxes]]></title>
        <id>609bcc6a62ab9107fe5a9f08</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-work-with-multiple-checkboxes-in-react/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T18:17:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Handling multiple checkboxes in React is completely different from how you use regular HTML checkboxes. So in this article, we'll see how to work with multiple checkboxes in React. You will learn: How to use a checkbox as a Controlled Input in ReactHow to use the array map and reduce]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Lawyer to Engineer at Google – How to Switch Careers and Learn New Skills]]></title>
        <id>609ccb0d62ab9107fe5aa0ce</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/from-lawyer-to-google-engineer/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T16:25:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was a corporate lawyer for 12 years. I never thought I'd be working at Google as a software engineer, but now I am. And I'm going to share with you ten important lessons I learned during this career transition. I finished law school in Bangalore, India, a year before]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced CSS Animation Using cubic-bezier()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340036</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/advanced-css-animation-using-cubic-bezier/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T14:24:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with complex CSS animations, there is a tendency to create expansive @keyframes with lots of declarations. There are a couple of tricks though that I want to talk about that might help make things easier, while staying in …
The post Advanced CSS Animation Using cubic-bezier() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SVGator 3.0 Reshapes the Way You Create and Animate SVG With Extensive New Features]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340118</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svgator-3-0-reshapes-the-way-you-create-and-animate-svg-with-extensive-new-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T14:24:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building animations can get complicated, particularly compelling animations where you aren’t just rolling a ball across the screen, but building a scene where many things are moving and changing in concert. When compelling animation is the goal, a timeline GUI …
The post SVGator 3.0 Reshapes the Way You Create and Animate SVG With Extensive New Features appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build and Deploy a Portfolio with Vue.js Axios, the GitHub REST API, and Netlify]]></title>
        <id>5fde208ae6787e09839407c3</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-a-portfolio-with-vuejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T20:53:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this free book, we will build two simple projects and deploy them on Netlify. We will use Vue.js as our front-end framework, and use different technologies to build our projects.  If you follow this tutorial to the end, you will build a simplified version of Twitter and a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use the Kivy Python Library to Create Games and Mobile Apps]]></title>
        <id>609c215862ab9107fe5a9fa9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/use-the-kivy-python-library-to-create-games-and-mobile-apps/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T18:49:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kivy is a free and open source Python framework for developing mobile apps and games with a natural user interface. We just released a 5-hour Kivy course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel. In this Kivy course, you will learn to create games and applications with Python for every platform]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Disabled Buttons More Inclusive]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339960</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/making-disabled-buttons-more-inclusive/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T14:31:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s talk about disabled buttons. Specifically, let’s get into why we use them and how we can do better than the traditional disabled attribute in HTML (e.g. <button disabled> ) to mark a button as disabled.
There are lots of …
The post Making Disabled Buttons More Inclusive appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandrina Pereira</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Selenium and Python to Scrape Websites More Effectively]]></title>
        <id>6096aafe2cd0545b5e944430</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/improve-web-scraping-with-selenium/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T22:53:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're scraping data from the web with Python, Selenium will often come up as an helpful tool to use. It was originally designed for automated testing, but its scraping capabilities are impressive, too. This is because Selenium can do things that other libraries or frameworks often can't when collecting]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Pie Timer Re-Revisited]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340359</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-pie-timer-re-revisited/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T22:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kitty reflected on an ancient blog post here on CSS-Tricks on how to make an animated pie timer. The old technique is still clever. The new technique is equally clever and much easier. I particularly like the steps() animation function…
The post CSS Pie Timer Re-Revisited appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I could build this during the weekend]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340186</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/joaoqalves/i-could-build-this-during-the-weekend-aa093c5e"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:04:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How many times have you heard that (or even uttered it under your own breath)? I know I’ve heard it in conversations. I also know I’ve wondered the same thing about a product or two — hey, the idea here …
The post I could build this during the weekend appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next Gen CSS: @container]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339138</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/next-gen-css-container/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T14:36:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome is experimenting with @container, a property within the CSS Working Group Containment Level 3 spec being championed by Miriam Suzanne of Oddbird, and a group of engineers across the web platform. @container brings us the ability to …
The post Next Gen CSS: @container appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Una Kravets</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340106</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/distributed-persistent-rendering-dpr/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T14:33:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like Jamstack, Netlify is coining this term.
If your reaction is: great, a new thing I need to know about and learn, know that while Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR) does involve some new things, this is actually a push …
The post Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topframe]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/topframe/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T21:14:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is extremely fun. Jeff Lindsay has created Topframe, and writes:
Anybody that knows how to mess around with HTML can now mess around with their desktop computing experience. Topframe is an open source tool that lets you 
…
The post Topframe appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating from Parcel to Snowpack]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340208</id>
        <link href="https://benfrain.com/migrating-from-parcel-to-snowpack-build-tool-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T21:13:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I find build tooling endlessly interesting, especially right now as we’re in a juicy next-gen transitional period with players like Vite, wmr, Snowpack, and esbuild. Hugh Haworth has a good run-down of the new players, and we’ve chatted on …
The post Migrating from Parcel to Snowpack appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variable Aspect Ratio Card With Conic Gradients Meeting Along the Diagonal]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339203</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/variable-aspect-ratio-card-with-conic-gradients-meeting-along-the-diagonal/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T14:13:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently came across an interesting problem. I had to implement a grid of cards with a variable (user-set) aspect ratio that was stored in a --ratio custom property. Boxes with a certain aspect ratio are a classic problem in …
The post Variable Aspect Ratio Card With Conic Gradients Meeting Along the Diagonal appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Tudor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vibe Check №4]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/05/vibe-check-4/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/05/vibe-check-4/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T22:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I turned 41 at the end of April. Another pandemic birthday in the books. This one was special thanks to grandparents coming to visit which allowed my wife and I to escape to a hotel for a night. A small relief to be off parenting duty for ~18 hours after fourteen months of so much parenting. We ate Korean food, drank cocktails, and watched Deadpool in our hotel room. A tranquil birthday.
April was a bit of a hangover from March work-wise. My project load carried over and, while they’re all great projects, I…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The OceanMaker]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/04/the-oceanmaker/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/04/the-oceanmaker/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-27T15:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s two features I look for in good sci-fi: 1. something I hadn’t imagined before and 2. something that anticipates the automobile, as well as the traffic jam. The YouTube gods smiled up me and surfaced a channel called DUST, a massive collection sci-fi short films. The quality is much better than what you might expect from “free sci-fi” but one of their films, The OceanMaker, is an absolute standout that raptured me and took me somewhere I’ve never been.
Extrapolating on the near future Water Wars, The…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>