<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-10T08:12:10.128Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-10T08:12:10.128Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.6.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine Learning Systems Book Recommendations – Learn How to Build and Understand ML Systems]]></title>
        <id>609558382cd0545b5e943c6f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/machine-learning-systems-book-recommendations/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T21:07:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Good friends, good books, and a sleepy conscience: this is the ideal life.” ― Mark TwainI hope you’re reading this blog in your pjs looking forward to a rejuvenating and healthy weekend.  I have been working on multiple projects lately, from creating Machine Learing Engineering and Machine Learning Operations courses]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recursion Might Seem Scary – But it Doesn&#x27;t Have to Be]]></title>
        <id>609551f02cd0545b5e943bc0</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/recursion-doesnt-have-to-be-scary/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T16:59:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Any concept that we don't fully understand can be scary at first. Recursion is a topic that programming students don't learn right away. But that doesn't mean it needs to be scary or cause anxiety. In fact, recursion is a concept that we can define rather simply. According to Wikipedia:]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is CSS a Programming Language?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339781</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/is-css-a-programming-language/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T13:56:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have a real distaste for this question. It might seem like a fun question to dig into on the surface, but the way it enters public discourse rarely seems to be in good faith. There are ulterior motives at &#8230;
The post Is CSS a Programming Language? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Typography]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339574</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-typography/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T13:54:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[These are a few great links about typography that have been burning a hole in my saved bookmarks folder that I'm just now getting around to sharing. There's good stuff in there, from how to choose typefaces for app design to ideas for how to fix the concept of font sizing in CSS.
The post Links on Typography appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can I Email…]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339822</id>
        <link href="https://www.caniemail.com/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T02:38:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While I&#8217;m 85% certain you&#8217;ve seen and used Can I Use&#8230;, I bet there is only a 13% chance that you&#8217;ve seen and used Can I Email&#8230;. It&#8217;s the same vibe—detailed support information for web platform features—except instead &#8230;
The post Can I Email&#8230; appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vibe Check №4]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/05/vibe-check-4/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/05/vibe-check-4/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T22:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I turned 41 at the end of April. Another pandemic birthday in the books. This one was special thanks to grandparents coming to visit which allowed my wife and I to escape to a hotel for a night. A small relief to be off parenting duty for ~18 hours after fourteen months of so much parenting. We ate Korean food, drank cocktails, and watched Deadpool in our hotel room. A tranquil birthday.
April was a bit of a hangover from March work-wise. My project load carried over and, while they’re all great projects, I…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Is &quot;Lifting State Up&quot; in React?]]></title>
        <id>609409c201fc34080ef81f97</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-lifting-state-up-in-react/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T21:41:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here is a simple and practical example what it means to "lift state up" in React, and how it can help you build your applications. Lifting state up is a common pattern that is essential for React developers to know. It helps you avoid more complex (and often unnecessary) patterns]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apparently, You Can Use Route53 as a Blazingly Fast Database]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340015</id>
        <link href="https://betterprogramming.pub/apparently-you-can-use-route53-as-a-blazingly-fast-database-dd416b56b005"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T20:03:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Route53 is DNS management service by AWS. DNS is absolutely not a database, and yet here&#8217;s Nicholas Martin writing up some very clever trickery originally done by Corey Quinn:
When you think about it, DNS configuration is actually a 
&#8230;
The post Apparently, You Can Use Route53 as a Blazingly Fast Database appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Google’s New Page Experience Update Means for Images on Your Website]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339936</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/what-googles-new-page-experience-update-means-for-images-on-your-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T19:57:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s easy to forget that, as a search engine, Google doesn’t just compare keywords to generate search results. Google knows that if people don’t enjoy their experience on a web page, they won’t stay on the page long enough to &#8230;
The post What Google’s New Page Experience Update Means for Images on Your Website appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn How to Use the Chrome DevTools to Troubleshoot Websites]]></title>
        <id>609415eb2cd0545b5e943534</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-how-to-use-the-chrome-devtools-to-troubleshoot-websites/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T16:26:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome DevTools is a set of web developer tools built directly into the Google Chrome browser. They can be super helpful for web developers. We just published a crash course that will teach you how to use Chrome DevTools to improve your productivity as a web developer. You will learn]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optional Types in Swift – How to Use and Unwrap Optionals]]></title>
        <id>60939bde01fc34080ef81a19</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/optional-types-in-swift/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T16:06:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're coming from Java, C++, or other object-oriented languages, chances are that you've never come across optional types or "optionals". And you might be quite surprised to know that such a concept exists in Swift. Optionals are a fundamental topic that you need to thoroughly understand to code in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom State Pseudo-Classes in Chrome]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339586</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/custom-state-pseudo-classes-in-chrome/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T14:28:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is an increasing number of “custom” features on the web platform. We have custom properties (--my-property), custom elements (&#60;my-element&#62;), and custom events (new CustomEvent('myEvent')). At one point, we might even get custom media &#8230;
The post Custom State Pseudo-Classes in Chrome appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Šime Vidas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beware the Cut ‘n’ Paste Persona]]></title>
        <id>https://alistapart.com/article/beware-the-cut-n-paste-persona/</id>
        <link href="https://alistapart.com/article/beware-the-cut-n-paste-persona/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This Person Does Not Exist is a website that generates human faces with a machine learning algorithm. It takes real portraits and recombines them into fake human faces. We recently scrolled past a LinkedIn post stating that this website could be useful “if you are developing a persona and looking for a photo.”&nbsp;
We agree: the computer-generated faces could be a great match for personas—but not for the reason you might think. Ironically, the website highlights the core issue of this very common design me…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>by ,</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Astro]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339563</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/astro/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T21:49:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can&#8217;t even look at code or documentation for Astro (publicly) yet — it&#8217;s an in-progress idea — but you can watch a video of Fred showing it off to Feross. 
I gotta admit: it looks awesome. I&#8217;m bullish &#8230;
The post Astro appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python and OpenCV Course –Create Computer Vision Apps in the Cloud]]></title>
        <id>609307e801fc34080ef8191e</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/create-computer-vision-apps-in-the-cloud-with-opencv-and-python/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T21:11:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCV is a library of programming functions mainly aimed at real-time computer vision.  We just published a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you how to use OpenCV in the cloud with Python. Misbah Mohammed created this course. He has a lot of experience with machine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Delayed Is Progress Denied]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339954</id>
        <link href="https://infrequently.org/2021/04/progress-delayed/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T16:51:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The bombshell article of the week is from Alex Russell of Google/Chrome. Alex has long been super critical of Apple, particularly about how there is literally no option to run any other browser than Safari on iOS. This article isn&#8217;t &#8230;
The post Progress Delayed Is Progress Denied appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Vendor Prefixing Dead?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339518</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/is-vendor-prefixing-dead/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T14:18:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let‘s take a quick stroll down memory-lane to revisit how vendor prefixing CSS properties came to be. I hope I don’t trigger PTSD for anyone!
It‘s not clear who started prefixing, or when it began exactly. What is clear, is &#8230;
The post Is Vendor Prefixing Dead? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob O'Leary</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[16px or Larger Text Prevents iOS Form Zoom]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339455</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/16px-or-larger-text-prevents-ios-form-zoom/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T21:16:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This was a great &#8220;Today I Learned&#8221; for me from Josh W. Comeau. If the font-size of an &#60;input&#62; is 16px or larger, Safari on iOS will focus into the input normally. But as soon as the font-size is &#8230;
The post 16px or Larger Text Prevents iOS Form Zoom appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jetpack Backup: Roll Back Your WooCommerce Site Without Losing Orders]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339867</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/jetpack-backup-roll-back-your-woocommerce-site-without-losing-orders/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T21:15:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s a dilemma: what happens if your WooCommerce site has a problem and the quickest and best way to fix it is to roll back to a previous version? The dilemma is, if you roll back the database, you would &#8230;
The post Jetpack Backup: Roll Back Your WooCommerce Site Without Losing Orders appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Node.js Async Await Tutorial – With Asynchronous JavaScript Examples]]></title>
        <id>609011fd8eb3fb07cf09a034</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/node-js-async-await-tutorial-with-asynchronous-javascript-examples/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T16:07:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A complete guide to Node.js async await]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copy a Directory in Linux – How to cp a Folder in the Command Line in Linux and Unix (MacOS)]]></title>
        <id>608f5ad48eb3fb07cf099ddb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/copy-a-directory-in-linux-how-to-cp-a-folder-in-the-command-line-in-linux-and-unix-macos/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T15:33:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To copy files or directories in Unix-based operating systems (Linux and MacOS), you use the cp command. The cp command is a relatively simple command, but its behavior changes slightly depending on the inputs (files vs directories) and the options you pass to it. To view the documentation or manual]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s use (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339449</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/lets-use-x-x-x-x-for-talking-about-specificity/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:19:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was just chatting with Eric Meyer the other day and I remembered an Eric Meyer story from my formative years. I wrote a blog post about CSS specificity, and Eric took the time to point out the misleading nature &#8230;
The post Let’s use (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Colorful, Smart Shadows]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339742</id>
        <link href="https://www.kirupa.com/html5/creating_colorful_smart_shadows.htm"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:19:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A bona fide CSS trick from Kirupa Chinnathambi here. To match a colored shadow with the colors in the background-image of an element, you inherit the background in a pseudo-element, kick it behind the original, then blur and filter it. &#8230;
The post Creating Colorful, Smart Shadows appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chapter 8: CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339419</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/chapter-8-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T21:52:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In June of 2006, web developers and designers from around the world came to London for the second annual @media conference. The first had been a huge success, and @media 2006 had even more promise. Its speaker lineup was pulled &#8230;
The post Chapter 8: CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Hoffmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Fetch Data in React from a GraphQL API]]></title>
        <id>6090187c8eb3fb07cf09a060</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/5-ways-to-fetch-data-react-graphql/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T17:20:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's go through the five best ways that you can fetch data with React from a GraphQL API. While there are a couple of popular libraries which are made to interact with GraphQL APIs from a React application, there are many different ways to fetch data with GraphQL. I've included]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Common Mistakes React Developers Make – And How to Fix Them]]></title>
        <id>608f553c8eb3fb07cf099da7</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/common-mistakes-react-developers-make-and-how-to-fix-them/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T16:40:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we'll see some of the common mistakes that React developers make, and how you can avoid them. So let's get started. Don't Forget that Every Route Change Mounts and Unmounts a ComponentWhenever you're using routing in a React application, you declare routes inside the Switch component. This]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Swipey Image Grids]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339384</id>
        <link href="https://www.cassie.codes/posts/swipey-image-grids/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T14:35:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hope people think of SVG as a vector format that is good for drawing things. There is plenty more to know, but here&#8217;s one more: SVG is good for composition. You draw things at very specific coordinates &#8230;
The post Swipey Image Grids appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Immersive Content Strategy]]></title>
        <id>https://alistapart.com/article/immersive-content-strategy/</id>
        <link href="https://alistapart.com/article/immersive-content-strategy/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beyond the severe toll of the coronavirus pandemic, perhaps no other disruption has transformed user experiences quite like how the tethers to our formerly web-biased era of content have frayed. We’re transitioning to a new world of remote work and digital content. We’re also experimenting with unprecedented content channels that, not too long ago, elicited chuckles at the watercooler, like voice interfaces, digital signage, augmented reality, and virtual reality.
Many factors are responsible. Perhaps it’s …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>by</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The OceanMaker]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/04/the-oceanmaker/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/04/the-oceanmaker/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-27T15:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s two features I look for in good sci-fi: 1. something I hadn’t imagined before and 2. something that anticipates the automobile, as well as the traffic jam. The YouTube gods smiled up me and surfaced a channel called DUST, a massive collection sci-fi short films. The quality is much better than what you might expect from “free sci-fi” but one of their films, The OceanMaker, is an absolute standout that raptured me and took me somewhere I’ve never been.
Extrapolating on the near future Water Wars, The…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do You Need to Localize Your Website?]]></title>
        <id>https://alistapart.com/article/do-you-need-to-localize-your-website/</id>
        <link href="https://alistapart.com/article/do-you-need-to-localize-your-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Global markets give you access to new customers. All you need to do is inform potential buyers about your product or service.&nbsp;
Your website is a good place to introduce your product or service outside your locale. Localizing your web content sounds like the right way to reach out to the global market. Localization will bridge the language barriers, or the wider scope of differing cultures.&nbsp;
Before we move on further with the discussion, let’s focus on the definition of “localization.”&nbsp;
What i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>by</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>