<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-23T05:44:00.483Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-23T05:44:00.483Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[inherit, initial, unset, revert]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342930</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/inherit-initial-unset-revert/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T21:20:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are four keywords that are valid values for any CSS property (see the title). Of those, day to day, I’d say I see the inherit used the most. Perhaps because it’s been around the longest (I think?) but also …
The post inherit, initial, unset, revert appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Scraping with PHP – How to Crawl Web Pages Using Open Source Tools]]></title>
        <id>60d2323d6e1a1407b6b0ac4f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/web-scraping-with-php-crawl-web-pages/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T21:11:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web scraping lets you collect data from web pages across the internet. It's also called web crawling or web data extraction.  PHP is a widely used back-end scripting language for creating dynamic websites and web applications. And you can implement a web scraper using plain PHP code.  But since we]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Async/Await to Write Better JavaScript Code]]></title>
        <id>60cac8ff4dc1a607ed7b4592</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-async-await-write-better-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T16:24:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a special syntax you can use in JavaScript that makes working with promises easier. It's called “async/await", and it’s surprisingly straightforward to understand and use.  In this article, we'll discuss:  What are asynchronus functions? How promises work in JavaScript Async/Await basics How to use]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use TypeScript and MongoDB to Build a 100 Days of Code Discord Bot]]></title>
        <id>60c13e71d3126007592d5be2</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-build-a-100-days-of-code-bot-for-discord-using-typescript-and-mongodb/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T16:20:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 100 Days of Code challenge is very popular among new coders and developers looking to level up their skills. It's so popular that our Discord server has an entire channel dedicated to it.  By popular demand, we recently built a Discord bot that helps people track their progress in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Python to Create a Visual Novel Game in 10 Minutes]]></title>
        <id>60cfff5a4dc1a607ed7b5e58</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/use-python-to-create-a-visual-novel/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T16:18:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you have a story idea that you'd like to turn into a novel? How about adding visual appeal and interactivity to that novel?  A Visual Novel might be the game genre you are looking for. And this tutorial is here to help set you up in 10 minutes, with]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Custom Elements in Svelte]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342634</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-custom-elements-in-svelte/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T14:37:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Svelte fully supports custom elements (e.g. <my-component>) without any custom configuration or wrapper components and has a perfect score on Custom Elements Everywhere. However, there are still a few quirks you need to watch out for, especially around …
The post Using Custom Elements in Svelte appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Rich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If we’re gonna criticize utility-class frameworks, let’s be fair about it]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342925</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/if-were-gonna-criticize-utility-class-frameworks-lets-be-fair-about-it/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T14:33:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m not here to raise a shield protecting CSS utility frameworks. I don’t even particularly like the approach, myself, and nothing is above fair criticism. But fair is a key word there. I can’t tell you how many times I’ve …
The post If we’re gonna criticize utility-class frameworks, let’s be fair about it appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Log Jams]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/06/log-jams/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/06/log-jams/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T13:27:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Fall 2020 to Spring 2021 I gave a talk about backlogs. It’s based on the story of the time someone assigned me 313 accessibility issues from an offshore audit. I believe every developer –at some point in their career– finds themselves pinned beneath a weighty backlog and because it’s such a universal experience, part of the job, I think it’s a topic worth discussing more frequently. And the parallel to a physical log jam was a portmanteau too perfect to pass up.
In the talk I explore how to break down work in a large backlog and introduce a tactic that I call “multidimensional audits”. There’s value in moving issues out of the bug tracker and into modern day spreadsheet tools so you can visualize your large problems from different angles. This helps make the backlog more digestible an…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Exit Vim – Vim Save and Quit Command Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>60c81f774dc1a607ed7b2f66</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-exit-vim/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:52:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've been using Vim since the first year I started coding. For all the IDEs/editors that I have used, the Vim plugin is always the very first plugin that I install. I know that Vim can be challenging to work in for people who are not familiar with it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python List Methods – append( ) vs extend( ) in Python Explained with Code Examples]]></title>
        <id>60bce157acb62507dd1d9f11</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/python-list-methods-append-vs-extend/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:25:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're working with Python lists, you often need to combine data from multiple lists. So how do you do that? In this tutorial, we'll see the different ways you can combine data from multiple lists. We'll also learn how the list methods append() and extend() work through simple examples.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are we in a new era of web design? What do we call it?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342887</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/new-responsive/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:22:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Una is calling it the new responsive. A nod to the era we were most certainly in, the era of responsive design. Where responsive design was fluid grids, flexible media, and media queries, the new responsive is those things …
The post Are we in a new era of web design? What do we call it? appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Redux by Making a Counter Application]]></title>
        <id>60cccd6e4dc1a607ed7b4f81</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-redux-by-making-a-counter-application/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Redux is a state management library for front end applications. Developers commonly use it with React through the react-redux package, but it can also stand alone – so you can use it in any front end framework or library, including Vanilla JavaScript.  Redux can really be intimidating at first. It might]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a Portfolio Website with React]]></title>
        <id>60d0d0ff6e1a1407b6b0a506</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-portfolio-website-react/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T18:15:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today you're going to create one of the most important apps you can build for yourself: your developer portfolio. Every React developer or web developer in general needs to be able to show off what they can do to any potential client or employer. That's exactly what we're going to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Figma? A Design Crash Course [2021 Tutorial]]]></title>
        <id>60cda7104dc1a607ed7b5588</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/figma-crash-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T17:52:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Figma is a powerful design tool that helps you to create anything: websites, applications, logos, and much more. By learning to use Figma, you'll take your first steps into User Interface Design and and User Experience Design. These skills are essential for building a great portfolio for yourself and potentially]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Technical Guide to IPFS – the Decentralized Storage of Web3]]></title>
        <id>60a55b37906c5207e3a7ea78</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/technical-guide-to-ipfs-decentralized-storage-of-web3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T16:38:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[But where do you store your application's content? Storing the content on the blockchain would be expensive and inefficient. Your blockchain application needs decentralized storage!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The perfect, more expensive, out-of-stock thing versus the less perfect, less expensive, in-stock thing.]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/06/two-options/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/06/two-options/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T15:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whenever my family attempts a major buying decision (TV, couch, computer, remodel, shed, dining table, etc) we’re inevitably confronted with a choice between two options:
The perfect, more expensive, but out-of-stock option
The less perfect, less expensive, in-stock option
This spins us out in a quandary of self-doubt. From the soul-seeking “Do we love it $700 more?”, to the hopefully naïve “What if they update it this year and it’s perfect?”, to the downright existential “Are we $700 more people?” We hem and haw, spinning around the issue like two black holes hoping to collide on a single opinion.
Almost always, we go with option two; the less perfect, less expensive, but in-stock option. Perhaps it’s us giving into impulsiveness, but there’s a small joy in walking away with a physical, tangible box or a tracking link instead of a lousy 12-digit order confirmation number. Even though we have enough datapoints to predict our behavior, we find ourselves in the same predicament over and over. Which path to take? Which path brings the most happiness? Which path is the secret to a happy lifestyle?
I know people who do the perfect, more expensive, but out-of-stock so they have to wait option and they seem happy with their perfect, expensive goods. But they must have a level of patience or perfection I do not. Did they perform better at the marshmallow experiment? Not that we’re unhappy with our on-time, lower grade wares. But I wonder what would happen if we were the people who went all out, exhausted the budget, and then waited weeks or months for the Platonic ideal to arrive. Eight more gigabytes. Eight more horsepower. Eight more threads per inch. Eight more florps. It must be worth it. It must be.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create CSS Charts With Interesting Shapes, Glyphs and Emoji]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342448</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-create-css-charts-with-interesting-shapes-glyphs-and-emoji/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T14:32:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s forego the usual circles and bars we typically see used in charts for more eccentric shapes. With online presentations more and more common today, a quick way to spruce up your web slides and make them stand out is …
The post How to Create CSS Charts With Interesting Shapes, Glyphs and Emoji appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Preethi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using the `outline` Property as a Collapsable Border]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341511</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-the-outline-property-as-a-collapsable-border/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T20:38:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The outline property in CSS draws a line around the outside of an element. This is quite similar to the border property, the main exception being that outline isn’t a part of the box model. It is often used for …
The post Using the `outline` Property as a Collapsable Border appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carter Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Typography]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342326</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-typography-2/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T13:44:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I studied the fonts of the top 1000 websites. Here’s what I learned. — Michael Li brings the data. San-serif has total dominance. “[…] it is rare to go below 10px or above 24px.” And poor <h5> always being the 
…
The post Links on Typography appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perfect Tooltips With CSS Clipping and Masking]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341948</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/perfect-tooltips-with-css-clipping-and-masking/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T14:45:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clipping and masking have been around for a while now in CSS and even have pretty decent browser support. I recently worked on a project that needed to use a clipping technique for tooltips showing above links in text.
Those …
The post Perfect Tooltips With CSS Clipping and Masking appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Louis Hoebregts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Start Serving Optimized Images in Vue]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342257</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/start-serving-optimized-images-in-vue/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T14:38:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have become extremely important to the effectiveness of websites. They speak a 1000 words, attract attention, and stimulate emotions.
However, web performance is also a growing problem for most websites. And images are at the heart of many web …
The post Start Serving Optimized Images in Vue appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ImageEngine</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inline Styles as Classes (lol)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342358</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/inline-styles-as-classes-lol/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T21:11:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re abhorred by using inline styles, just move that style to the class attribute! And then make sure you have CSS in place that, ya know, does what it says on the box. 
I've revolutionized CSS. pic.twitter.com/1AWCldyCwP
— Sam 

…
The post Inline Styles as Classes (lol) appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful and Useless Code Comments]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342630</id>
        <link href="https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2021/useful-and-usless-code-comments/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T19:08:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jim Nielsen: 
If somebody says a comment isn’t adding any value, I would ask: to whom?
Personally, I’ve never liked the advice that writing obvious comments is bad practice—probably because I write obvious comments all the time.
Jim showed …
The post Useful and Useless Code Comments appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Used the WAAPI to Build an Animation Library]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342353</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-i-used-the-waapi-to-build-an-animation-library/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T14:26:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Web Animations API lets us construct animations and control their playback with JavaScript. The API opens the browser’s animation engine to developers and was designed to underlie implementations of both CSS animations and transitions, leaving the door open to …
The post How I Used the WAAPI to Build an Animation Library appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Okiki Ojo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detect Unused Classes in… HTML]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342198</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/detect-unused-classes-in-html/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T23:24:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Usually, when “unused” comes up in conversation regarding CSS, it’s about removing chunks of CSS that are not used in your site or, at least, the styles not currently in use on a specific page. The minimal amount of CSS …
The post Detect Unused Classes in… HTML appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Media Queries in Times of @container]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342519</id>
        <link href="https://mxb.dev/blog/media-queries-in-times-of-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T19:51:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Max Böck took me up on my challenge to look through a codebase and see how many of the @media queries could ultimately become @container queries.
I took the bait and had a look at some of my projects – 
…
The post Media Queries in Times of @container appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just How Niche is Headless WordPress?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342248</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/just-how-niche-is-headless-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T14:31:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I wonder where headless WordPress will land. And by “headless” I mean only using the WordPress admin and building out the user-facing site through the WordPress REST API rather than the traditional WordPress theme structure.
Is it… big? The future …
The post Just How Niche is Headless WordPress? appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Amnesia Fortnight Documentary]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/06/the-amnesia-fortnight-documentary/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/06/the-amnesia-fortnight-documentary/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T17:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of my favorite game studios, Double Fine Productions, hosts and documents their internal 2-week game jam which they call “Amnesia Fortnight”. While it may be stressful for a small company to stop production on their monetization pipeline, Double Fine sees it as a way to test out “experimental” ideas and give people who aren’t game directors a shot at directing a game. A chance for people to play a different or larger role than what they typically perform. It also provides employees a break from the daily grind.
I love the ethos of game jams because they force you to distill an idea down to its essence. The goal isn’t to have a polished, marketable product at the end, it’s to have something people can play. There’s a small plan, a lot of improv, and a lot of self-editing. If you can’t r…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vibe Check №5]]></title>
        <id>https://daverupert.com/2021/06/vibe-check-5/</id>
        <link href="https://daverupert.com/2021/06/vibe-check-5/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T18:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two vibes dominated this month: Work and Refinancing my house (which is more work). Work continues to be busy, a constant refrain, but this past half-year has been some of the hardest I’ve worked in my whole life. The tl;dr is that it’s hard to build a startup and do client projects at the same time. On top of that this month my wife and I are refinancing our house. Refinancing your house as a self-employed person is a special kind of hell with a heaping amount of extra “ASAP!”-type work added to your busy schedule.
The refinance is temporary and should die down soon and I’m finding some work boundaries and systems that help me organize my work week on a meta level (e.g. I work on project X  on day Y). Speaking candidly, it hasn’t been a great month for me but I do get to work with great p…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daverupert.com</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>